我希望你从中得到的唯一一点是有一些属性，并且
The only point that I want you to take from this is there are properties, and
这就是我们努力做这些事情的原因。
that's why we we strive to do this stuff.
我们有关联性，我们有身份。
We have associativity, we have identity.
有一种叫做同态的东西，我们实际上可以将幺半群放入并
There's a thing called a homomorphism, where we can actually take a monoid in and
对另一个幺半群做类型转换。
do a type transformation to another monoid.
并且这些属性仍将保持不变。
And the properties would still hold.
这里只是一个幺半群同态的例子。
And here's a just an example of a monoidal homomorphism.
我们在这里有一条消息。
Where here we have a message.
然后我们将从字符串中解析该消息，然后我们调用 MergeFrom。
And then we're gonna parse that message from a string, and then we call MergeFrom.
所以看起来这里发生的事情是，
So it looks like what's happening here is,
我们实际上可以解析消息，解析其他消息并合并它。
we can actually parse the message, and parse the other message and merge it.
或者我们可以组合消息然后解析它，两者都是幺半群。
Or we can combine the messages and then parse it, and both are monoids.
我们能够做出让事情更有效率的决定。
And we're able to make decisions on making things more efficient.
首先组合它们然后进行类型转换，或者组合
By first combining them and then doing the type transformation, or combining
它们全部，或者先进行类型转换，然后再组合它们。
them all, or doing the type transformation first and then combining them.
好的，Cayley 定理非常棒，但我们不会处理它。
Okay, Cayley's Theorem is pretty great, but we're not gonna deal with it.
单子是内函子范畴中的幺半群，
And monads are monoids in the category of endofunctors,
您可以将链视为嵌套。
you can think of chain as in nesting.
所以如果我在一个类型中有一个类型并且
So if I have a type within a type and
我可以展平那种类型，这是一个幺半群运算。
I can flatten that type, that's a monoidal operation.
我们正在结合它们。
We're combining them.
所以这就是手波浪，有点简而言之，单子是幺半群。
So that's how hand wavy, kinda nutshell way, the monads are monoids.